ADRIAN WELCH

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACTS



(M) adriancwelch@gmail.com



github.com/adrianwelch



AN adriancwelch.co.uk



in linkedin.com/in/adrianwelch

KEY SKILLS

In order of confidence

JavaScript

jQuery

HTML5

CSS3 & SCSS

Ruby

Ruby on Rails

AngularJS

Node.js

Express

Mongoose

MongoDB

SQL

Adobe Premiere Pro

Advanced in Thai

PROFILE

A dynamic, adaptable graduate with the hunger to learn and progress a career in web development. I recently graduated with a Business Management degree from University of Birmingham with uncertainty in career path. After experiences in corporate events/PR, I decided it wasn't really for me, and I should pursue a career where I am excited to go to work every day.

I decided a career in development is right for me because technology has always fascinated me since a very young age. The fact that there are no limits in creativity and problem solving gives me pure excitement with the incredible opportunities and fast pace environment in this industry. I believe my desire to learn would make me a promising developer.

DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

Travelog

Languages/Packages: AngularJS, Ruby on Rails, PostgresSQL, HTML, jQuery, Sass

https://github.com/adrianwelch/project-4-frontend https://github.com/adrianwelch/project-4-api

Being so eager to travel when the opportunity arises, I felt I had to build a travel app as my final project at GA. This was my first project built using two separate languages for front-end (AngularJS) and back-end (Ruby on Rails). Travelog allows users to create trips and add legs within their trip while they are travelling. I used Google's API to grab the location of each of user's legs and place them on custom markers on the map. As each leg is added, a polyline is created to join the whole trip. I also linked the latitude and longitude grabbed from the user's location of each leg to make Skyscanner requests and display available flights.

Buff

Languages/Packages: AngularJS, AJAX and APIs https://github.com/AliceMarshall/project-3

My team and I decided to build an app that would help users plan a date night by entering their date information including both party's locations. We used Google and Cinemas Listing API to give the user the closest cinemas available within 2 miles to allow both parties to meet in the middle. When the cinema is chosen, the user is then given the option to pick restaurants within 100 metres of the chosen cinema. As I am more comfortable building front-end, I decided to test myself and focus more of the back-end of this project to build my confidence.

ADRIAN WELCH

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

QUALIFICATIONS

General Assembly
(Jan 2017 – April 2017)

Web Development Immersive Course

University of Birmingham (Oct 2012 - June 2015)

Bsc Business Management

INTERESTS

I love to follow and play sports. I am currently in a weekly 5 a side football league. I also frequently play tennis having played competitive from a young age and plan to learn golf this summer.

I always set out a plan of where I would like to travel next when it would be feasible. I love to explore new cultures and places around the world which is why I travelled for 9 months.

DiveBook

Languages/Packages: Express.js, Node and MongoDB

https://github.com/adrianwelch/wdi25-project-2

Being a keen scuba-diver, I built an app that would allow fellow divers to log their dives and comment on other users' dives to share their experiences around the world. I used the CRUD/RESTful concepts for my resources. Users are able to see all the dives created on the database on markers on Google Maps. I used AWS for the first time to allow users to upload images of their dives.

Penalty Click-out

Languages/Packages: HTML, CSS, Javascript https://github.com/adrianwelch/Project-1

As a massive football fan, I built a penalty shootout game but with targets! The user must click as many targets that randomly appear for 30 seconds. I thoroughly enjoyed the challenge of using JavaScript for the first time to build game logic and adding cool features such as sound and animations!

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Developer, General Assembly (Jan 2017 – April 2017)

Full-time immersive course in web development, covering a structured web programming curriculum delivered by industry experts. A course that not only teaches code but the ability to learn code. Concentrating on the MEAN stack and Ruby, working with Agile methodologies within groups was a fantastic introduction to coding.

Intern, WBR (Oct 2016 - Dec 2016)

Production intern for Worldwide Business Research, an organisation specialising in corporate events globally. I helped liaise with potential and confirmed speakers for upcoming events. Communication was a key skill needed for this role as well as managing key content on the company website and app.

Intern, LDA Communications (Aug 2015 – October 2015)

Intern at established consultancy working in TV, entertainment, film, celebrity and brands. I worked closely on Ledly King's testimonial project, communicating with sponsors and donors to collect raffle prizes and donations. I also managed their social media accounts including company website, Twitter and LinkedIn.